PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: BELINDA MUSANGI NYAMAI

PHONE NUMBER: 0706807857

EMAIL: belinda.nyamai@gmail.com

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an Economics and Statistics graduate conversant with the use of several computer analysis software like; Advanced Excel, SPSS, STATA and R-GUI. This evidently proves my ability to evaluate and conduct quantitative data analysis while encouraging progression in key areas of an organization. Moreover, accounting has impacted in me the necessity of establishing and maintaining financial records that are up to date and reliable for future reference. Additionally, I have worked as a junior researcher hence an understanding of what it takes to perform various data related tasks. My qualifications show without doubt that all assigned roles will be conducted to the required standards.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Software programming
- Statistical modelling
- Machine learning
- Financial management

EDUCATION EXPERIENCE

2022-2023: DATA SCIENCE

MORINGA SCHOOL - NAIROBI.

2018-2021: BACHELOR OF ECONOMICS AND STATISTICS

THE UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI – NAIROBI, MAIN CAMPUS

SECOND CLASS HONOURS UPPER DIVISION

2020-2020: STATISTICAL PACKAGE FOR DATA SCIENCES

SPSS, STATA, ADVANCED EXCEL, R-GUI

DALWORTH STATISTICAL AND RESEARCH TRAINING CENTRE - NAIROBI, CBD

2019-2019: CPA SECTION 2

VISION INSTITUTE OF PROFESSIONALS – NAIROBI, CBD

2018-2018: CPA SECTION 1

STRATHMORE UNIVERSITY- NAIROBI, MAKADARA

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022-2022: KENYA NATIONAL BUREAU OF STATISTICS

POSITION: JUNIOR RESEARCHER; KENYA DEMOGRAPHIC HEALTH SURVEY 2022

- •Locating structures and households in sample clusters.
- •Identifying eligible respondents in selected households and appropriately issuing questionnaires.
- •Ensuring data confidentiality is guaranteed before data collection.
- •Editing completed questionnaires to ensure accurate recording of responses.
- •Keeping a record of callbacks to access progress and address challenges.

2022-2023: SOLUTION POINT INSURANCE AGENCY

POSITION: ASSISTANT ACCOUNTANT

- •Performing risk management by analyzing liabilities and management.
- •Maintaining accounts for the company as per International Financial Reporting Standards.
- •Liaising with external auditors to facilitate annual audits.
- •Ensuring cost management and revenue optimization strategies are implemented.
- •Preparing and presenting monthly financial statement analysis.

REFERENCES

JOSHUA MBITI NGENE

KNIGHT FRANK KENYA LIMITED

SENIOR ACCOUNTANT

Telephone; 0727758394

Email; joshua.ngene@ke.knightfrank.com

MARY MUASYA MUTETI

TETI PHARMACY

PHARMACY MANAGER

Telephone; 0718732846

Email; inahvekiteti@gmail.com